We're going to practice observing
冠状硬膜の観察について練習します。
the coronal dural sheath in relation to the symphysis and the
冠状硬膜の観察について、結合と
maxilla.
上顎骨との関係についてです。
We'll simply observe how these fields settle, but for that, you'll need to be
これらの場がどのように定着するかを見るだけですが、そのためには
on an electrical level.
電気的なレベルに身を置く必要があります。
This is also how we treat tendons, tendinitis.
腱炎などの腱の治療もこのように行います。
change many things. As long as you haven't reset
多くのことを変えることができます。電流を戻さない限り、
the electrical currents, it won't work.
電流が流れなければ、何も起こりません。
And when we see this placement
そして、この配置を見ると、
of the base of the skull, which is the neurocranium
頭蓋底は神経頭蓋です。
in relation
それに対して、
to the viscerocranium. It's as if
内臓頭蓋。まるで
your visceral system was supported
あなたの内臓システムが
at the base of the skull, like a
頭蓋底で支えられているかのようです。
And above,
そして上には、
I have my brain
私の脳があります。
which is the neurocranium.
それが神経頭蓋です。
And between the two, I have this.
そしてその間に、これがあります。
And then, I can't
そして、私は
go directly to this base of the skull.
この頭蓋底に直接行くことはできません。
However, I can reach it through the periphery.
しかし、周辺からなら到達できます。
Since we know that all my
なぜなら、私のすべての
dural membranes
硬膜の膜は、
of tension all come
すべて
to attach to the base of my skull.
頭蓋底に付着しているからです。
They are like moored.
それらは固定されています。
I will first take my
まず、私の
coronal suture and I will take
冠状縫合を取り、
the part here that we call
ここにある部分、
the maxilla.
上顎骨を取ります。
Okay?
いいですか？
I'm putting myself on that level.
このレベルに身を置きます。
Maxillo.
上顎骨。
zygomatic, actually, you see.
頬骨、実際には、ほら。
And I'll be there.
そして、私はそこにいます。
And there, I also have a sheath, actually, that does this.
そして、そこにも鞘があります。
And which also comes, in fact, it's a line that also comes towards the base of the skull.
そして、それも頭蓋底に向かう線です。
They're like rings.
それはリングのようです。
The two rings must meet and be in connection, if you will, you see.
2つのリングは出会い、接続されている必要があります。
And the electrical level is a subtle level where it's like it's on or off, actually.
そして、電気的なレベルとは、オンかオフのような微妙なレベルです。
Don't forget, this coronal suture is quite low, because there are many who are there.
忘れないでください、この冠状縫合はかなり低い位置にあります。なぜなら、たくさんあるからです。
We're going to go quite well on this coronal suture, where Bregma was.
この冠状縫合、ブレグマがあった場所をかなりうまく進んでいきます。
because if it's alive, there are thermal exchanges
なぜなら、それが生きているなら、熱交換があるからです。
there's still a heat that impacts
やはり熱が影響しています。
she can also feel it gently
彼女もそっと感じることができます。
there's a point a bit on the line
線上に少し点があります。
where there's a small energy loss
エネルギーの小さな損失がある場所です。
there, what you feel
ほら、あなたが感じているのはこれです。
now, I'm going to make you feel
今からあなたに感じさせます。
I'm going to put it on the electrical frequency
電気周波数に合わせます。
there I put myself on this ring
今、このリングに合わせます。
there I have this connection
今、このつながりがあります。
I go towards this spheno-basilar symphysis
この蝶形骨結合に向かいます。
so here I can already say
だから、ここで私はすでに言うことができます。
look, it's vital, it's warm
ほら、これは生命力があり、暖かいです。
responds. There is still a little work that will be done in this
応答します。やはり、この動きの中で少し作業が行われます。
movement here, we'll see. I
ここでは、見てみましょう。私は今、彼女の頬骨弓の部分と接続します。
will now connect with the part of her maxillo-zygomatic
ここでは、このように、
here, like this,
これもまた、まるでこの2つのリングが出会うかのように、向かってきます。
which also comes towards... it's as if these two rings meet
実際には。だから、すでに2つの間には違いがあります。すでに上の方で少し損失があります。だから、
actually. So already between
やはり、
the two there is a difference, there is already a bit of a loss at the top, so
疲労があり、闘いがあります。すぐに、私は彼女の副腎にいます。たとえ私がここにいても、間接的な副腎の関係があります。だから、ここでは、少しバッテリーを充電する必要があります。
there is still a...
女性の場合。例えば、ここで、私がここにいて、診察でそれを感じるとき、すぐに私は彼女の副腎に合わせ、副腎を温めます。私は
fatigue, there's a struggle. Right away, I'm on her adrenals. Even if I'm
ここの靭帯を解放し、副腎を充電するためにこのようにします。
here, there's an indirect adrenal connection. So here, we need to recharge the
その後、心臓システム全体、
batteries
つまり内皮系全体との関係を築きます。
for madam. For example, here, when I'm there and I feel that in consultation, right
左右の内頸動脈、
away, I put myself on her adrenals and I warm up the adrenals. I
左右の椎骨動脈、そして脳底動脈系という4つの入り口にどのように働きかけることができるか。
release
それらがどのように反応するか、
the ligaments here and I would put myself like this to recharge
もし私たちがそれらを正しく触れ、
the adrenals.
心臓に関して、あるいは時には心臓に関してそれらを解放できるなら。
Afterwards, we will make the connection with the entire cardiac system,
その後、心臓システム全体、
so the entire endothelial system,
つまり内皮系全体との関係を築きます。
how we can work on the four entry points,
左右の内頸動脈、
which are the left and right internal carotid,
左右の椎骨動脈、そして脳底動脈系という4つの入り口にどのように働きかけることができるか。
and left and right vertebral, then the basilar system,
それらがどのように反応するか、
with how reactive they are,
もし私たちがそれらを正しく触れ、
if we touch them correctly,
心臓に関して、あるいは時には心臓に関してそれらを解放できるなら。
even to the vitelline umbilical system, so mesenteric
臍帯卵黄系、つまり腸間膜系にまで及ぶ
or splenic on the sinus of the heart.
または心臓の洞にある脾臓。
I work with four energies, with the energy of weight or gravity,
私は4つのエネルギー、つまり重力または引力のエネルギーを使って仕事をしています。
to restore a proper contact. Either some people are too heavy, they are already buried, or some people are even too light, they float. Then the energy of the midline, then the energy of the energetic body. pure. Here we are more on this electrical plane. What we feel is vibratory. And here again coronal. I wait and then I will see again here. Here again, I already have more vitality. It's not yet 100% but it's already better. There was a void. So it's the hammock of the eye. There, you see, there was a strain. The entire upper axis, so everything was in strain. There, who would that be? Do you feel that? It's as if it made a... I'm exaggerating, but it was like that. When I recognized the tissue, it has its reference point. There is induction. There is movement in ease. I'm not in movement in ease, I'm in presence. OK, first level. Second level, I'm going to work canino, maxillo, three fingers. At the level of my frontal boss. I have an axis like this. I need good support points, otherwise my hand will be unbalanced. There, I feel again. If I feel this warmth and this vibration, and if it's well in the plane. I'm looking for my frontal boss. There, which is here. I look. I stay here. Now, I'm here. There, I take at the same time the line here, and at the same time the line here. You see, the zygomatico-frontal boss line homolateral. So like that, I have two levels. Here, I have a good warmth, I have a good field. Here, it's more diminished. I'm going to look here, at the level of the coronal suture. I'm going to palpate my coronal suture, there, here, there, it's quite, there, here, just a little bit it can block a bit sometimes it makes a canine-maxillary nail here frontal and like that There, it passes. It's not yet how I would like it on the right. I'm looking. As I would like, as... Here, on the other side. Canine, canine. Axillo. Frontal, here, start. And then, here, and there. There's really... It's this axis here that's disturbed. So there's an energy loss here. Maybe it's slower to work. That's why it will heal faster. So here, what I've found each time, it's always in this axis. A bit of a loss of vitality, so to speak. And a bit on the coronal structure that I had a little bit at the beginning that was busy looking. So it's busy rebalancing like that. Third level, which we're doing now, renunciation of flexion. The mastoids. You shouldn't press too hard. There, she has a mastoid, she has a small torsion like that. One is a bit more anterior than the other, if you will. I'm going to see if it's a point of change and balance. And there, I can go into induction or facilitated movement. Here, it's a technique of slight induction. I follow her extension. Oops, she goes into flexion. And I accompany her flexion. And there, I press. When I put myself in these things, here, I observe her breathing. And if I want to go into a point of change, I observe her expiratory pause. Sometimes, people make a... Subtitling Radio-Canada What is that? Change of polarity. They take an inspiration and a big breath. So they make an oxidation, a change of redox.
適切な接触を回復するために。
pure. Here we are more on this electrical plane. What we feel is vibratory. And
純粋な。ここでは、私たちはこの電気的な平面にいます。私たちが感じるのは振動です。そして
here again
ここから
coronal. I wait and then I will see again here. Here again,
再び冠状。私は待って、そしてここで再び見直します。ここから
I already have more
再び、私はすでに多くの
vitality. It's not yet 100% but it's already better. There was a void. So
活力。まだ100%ではありませんが、すでに良くなっています。空虚がありました。だから
it's the hammock of
それは
the eye. There, you see, there was a strain. The entire upper axis,
目のハンモックです。ほら、あなたはそこに緊張があったのを見ました。すべての上部軸
so everything was in strain.
つまり、すべてが緊張していました。
There, who would that be? Do you feel that?
ほら、これは誰でしょう？感じますか？
It's as if it made a...
まるでそれが...
I'm exaggerating, but it was like that.
大げさに言っていますが、そんな感じでした。
When I recognized the tissue,
私が組織を認識したとき、
it has its reference point.
それはその参照点を持っています。
There is induction.
誘導があります。
There is movement in ease.
容易な動きがあります。
I'm not in movement in ease,
私は容易な動きの中にいません。
I'm in presence.
私は存在の中にいます。
OK, first level.
OK、最初のレベル。
Second level, I'm going to work
2番目のレベルでは、私は作業します
canino, maxillo,
犬歯、上顎、
three fingers.
3本の指。
At the level of my frontal boss.
私の前頭隆起のレベルで。
I have an axis like this.
私にはこのような軸があります。
I need good support points,
良い支点が必要です。
otherwise my hand will be unbalanced.
さもないと、私の手は不安定になります。
There, I feel again.
ここで、私は再び感じます。
If I feel this warmth and this vibration,
もし私がこの熱とこの振動を感じるなら、
and if it's well in the plane.
そしてそれが平面内にあるなら。
I'm looking for my frontal boss.
私は自分の前頭隆起をよく探します。
There, which is here.
ほら、ここにある。
I look.
私は見ます。
I stay here.
私はここにいます。
Now, I'm here.
今、私はここにいます。
There, I take at the same time the line here,
そこで、私は同時にここの線を取り、
and at the same time the line here.
そして同時にここの線を取ります。
You see, the zygomatico-frontal boss line
ご覧の通り、頬骨と前頭隆起の線は
homolateral.
同側です。
So like that, I have two levels.
だから、このようにして、私は2つのレベルを持っています。
Here, I have a good warmth, I have a good field.
ここは良い暖かさがあり、良い場があります。
Here, it's more diminished.
ここは少し減少しています。
I'm going to look here, at the level of the coronal suture.
ここで、冠状縫合のレベルを見てみましょう。
I'm going to palpate my coronal suture, there, here, there,
冠状縫合を触診します。ここです。
it's quite, there, here, just a little bit
ここはかなり、ここが少しだけ
it can block a bit
少し詰まることがあります。
sometimes it makes a canine-maxillary nail
時には、それが犬歯と上顎の
here frontal and like that
前頭骨のようになります。
There, it passes.
はい、通ります。
It's not yet how I would like it on the right.
まだ右側は思い通りではありません。
I'm looking.
探しています。
As I would like, as...
思い通りに、まるで...
Here, on the other side.
反対側では。
Canine, canine.
犬歯、犬歯。
Axillo.
上顎。
Frontal, here, start.
前頭骨、ここから始まります。
And then, here, and there.
そして、ここ、そしてそこ。
There's really...
本当に...
It's this axis here that's disturbed.
この軸が乱れています。
So there's an energy loss here.
だから、ここにエネルギーの損失があります。
Maybe it's slower to work.
もしかしたら、作業が遅いのかもしれません。
That's why it will heal faster.
だから、それはより早く治癒するでしょう。
So here, what I've found each time, it's always in this axis.
だから、ここで私が毎回見つけたのは、この軸の中に毎回あったということです。
A bit of a loss of vitality, so to speak.
いわば、活力のわずかな喪失。
And a bit on the coronal structure that I had a little bit
そして、私が少し持っていた冠状構造に少し
at the beginning that was busy looking.
最初から探していたものです。
So it's busy rebalancing like that.
だから、それはこのように再均衡しようとしています。
Third level, which we're doing now,
今行う3番目のレベルは、
renunciation of flexion.
屈曲の放棄です。
The mastoids.
乳様突起。
You shouldn't press too hard.
あまり強く押しすぎないでください。
There, she has a mastoid, she has a small torsion like that.
はい、彼女は乳様突起を持っていて、このように少しねじれています。
One is a bit more anterior than the other, if you will.
もしよろしければ、片方がもう片方よりも少し前方にあります。
I'm going to see if it's a point of change and balance.
それが変化とバランスの点であるかどうかを見てみましょう。
And there, I can go into induction or facilitated movement.
そして、そこで私は誘導または促進された動きに入ることができます。
Here, it's a technique of slight induction.
これは軽い誘導のテクニックです。
I follow her extension.
私は彼女の延長です。
Oops, she goes into flexion.
ほら、彼女は屈曲します。
And I accompany her flexion.
そして私は彼女の屈曲に寄り添います。
And there, I press.
そしてそこで、私は押します。
When I put myself in these things, here,
私がこれらのことに入るとき、ここで、
I observe her breathing.
私は彼女の呼吸を観察します。
And if I want to go into a point of change,
そしてもし私が変化のポイントに行きたいなら、
I observe her expiratory pause.
私は彼女の呼気終末を観察します。
Sometimes, people make a...
時々、人々は...
Subtitling Radio-Canada
Société Radio-Canada 字幕
What is that?
これは何ですか？
Change of polarity.
極性の変化。
They take an inspiration and a big breath.
彼らは吸気をして大きく息を吐きます。
So they make an oxidation, a change of redox.
つまり、彼らは酸化、酸化還元反応の変化を起こしているのです。